GRACE YUNANTASSA FIRGIA

Jakarta, Indonesia • +62823-2842-5566 • gracellata@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/grace-firgia/

SUMMARY

A web developer with solid experience in both front-end and back-end development. Comfortable working independently or as part of a team. Proficient in React.js, Next.js, Node.js, and Nest.js, using MySQL, PostgreSQL, and REST APIs in day-to-day work. Currently exploring data and Al technologies to expand skill sets and apply them to real-world projects.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, PT Bithealth Teknologi Pintar (Bithealth)

Mar 2023 - Present

- Develop and optimize a *Human Capital Management System (HCMS)* used by over 13,000 users, focusing on improving system performance and user experience.
- Develop and optimize a *Hospital Information System (HIS)* with an integrated *Electronic Medical Record (EMR)*, used by over 5 major hospitals and 100+ clinics, focused on developing high-performance solutions and reusable components to streamline healthcare operations.
- Successfully reduced report generating time from 3 hours to just 2 minutes by re-engineering data handling algorithms and optimizing database queries, leading to significant improvements in operational efficiency.
- Designed and implemented RESTful APIs for integration with third-party services, reducing manual processing by 30%.
- Reduced application load times by 25% through performance optimization techniques, leading to a better user experience.
- Conducted code reviews and mentored junior developers, fostering a culture of best practices and continuous improvement.

Stacks.

Typescript, Next.js, Nest.js, React.js, Express.js, Postgresql, Mongodb, TypeORM, Sequelize, Tailwind, RabbitMQ

Fullstack Developer, PT Erakomp Infonusa

Jul 2022 - Mar 2023

- Plan and manage project timelines, reducing delivery times by 30%.
- Managing the complete software development process from conception to deployment.
- Managing the end-to-end life cycle for the production of software and applications.
- Overseeing and guiding the analyzing, writing, building, and deployment of software
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams, enhancing project success rates by 10%.

Stacks.

Javascript, Nuxt.js, Vue.js, Express.js, Mysql, Sequelize

Fullstack Developer, PT Galactic Multimedia (Oomph)

Mar 2022 - Jul 2022

- Built innovative microservices and Web Services (incl. REST).
- Producing, maintaining, and modifying websites and user interfaces.
- Ensuring websites are accessible across many platforms, including laptops and smartphones.
- Work across functions, collaborate with other engineers, as well as product design and ideation

Stacks:

PHP, Code Igniter 3, Mysql, Sequelize

Software Engineer, Lumbung Nusa

Aug 2020 - Feb 2022

- Team up with the UI/UX designer and bridge the gap between graphical design and technical implementation, taking an active role on both sides and defining how the application looks and works.
- Responsible for translation of the UI/UX design wireframes to actual code that will produce visual elements of the application.
- Developed and maintained web applications for a leading e-commerce platform, focusing on improving user experience and performance.
- Responsible for developing the Lumbung Kurir App, Lumbungnusa's courier application and warehouse system.

Stacks:

Javascript, Vue.js, Express.js, MySQL, Sequelize, Capacitor

Fullstack Developer, Freelance

2019 - Present

- · Company Profile
- Petshop Grooming Booking App
- Library Information System
- · SPM Rental Motor Website
- EPT Toefl Booking Website using Midtrans payment gateway
- Desa Ranggo Infrastructure Rental Website
- E-commerce with Midtrans payment gateway
- Bantuan Pangan Distribution App

Stacks:

Javascript, Vue.js, Express.js, MySQL, Sequelize, Flutter 3, Golang

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer

Aug 2017 - May 2022

Universitas Teknologi Yogyakarta Informatika - Fakultas Teknologi Informasi dan Elektro

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Skills: Project Management, Fullstack Development, Web Design, Query, Mobile Development
- Programming Languages: PHP, Javascript, Typescript, Flutter (Dart), Python, Golang
- Development Practices: Agile Scrum
- Tools: Git, Jira, Trello
- · Languages: Indonesia, English